hey y'all so we are about to um sign on with greg stoker after that i am going to be over on um
on uh substack doing a reading from my play i don't know why it's not working oh there it is
you're on a boat i am on a boat and look there's sails and everything it's the whole shebang
it looks very legit how are you guys holding up well uh definitely better than the first night
we launched we hit some we hit a storm it was like actually like 40 mile wind so it was a gale
it was uh a lot of first time first people's time on the open ocean and it was not pleasant for a
lot of people we had a lot of i face planted on the deck a lot of people threw up yeah a lot a lot
of the kitchen supplies um and the galley like came unsecured and so there's like pots and pans banging
around with the waves it was a it was a hell of a hell of a way to start this uh this little endeavor
yeah but but now now the now it's nice calm waters so where where where are you guys now
i saw that the folks the both of tunisia were starting to join you yeah well they're getting
ready they're gonna have the same mechanical issues that uh we were dealing with uh when we
first launched because again this whole thing this whole endeavor now that the final solution is
being enacted in gaza was caught uh was really uh cobbled together over the past two months and we had
to launch now because you can't really uh sail the mediterranean um after like september so it's like
we had to launch now so we're dealing with a lot of like mechanical issues logistical issues
so we've had a couple kinks but working them out and we're on the way to tunis the uh the port of
carthage that was okay um so far has there been anything that you didn't suspect that you didn't
expect that um you know that you're experiencing um not really uh we you know the the freedom flotilla
coalition has been around for a very very long time and you know right uh i believe it's the 39th
yeah so uh there's a long history and archive of precedence of what they will and will not do
and because you know okay they've only got like they like they're a hammer so they treat everything
like it's a nail and their playbook's really easy to anticipate so earlier uh like a couple days ago we
expect like psychological operations to dissuade us and bureaucratic warfare like that's one of the
big things that we've uh been dealing with like the israeli government pressuring the spanish
government and the italian government to like deny ships licenses shut down the ports pull people's
flags because you have to have a flag to sail in international waters uh that failed at least in
spain uh so president herzog president herzog the uh the president of israel uh isaac herzog is flying
to rome to ostensibly meet the pope to discuss like anti-semitism and you know uh in israel and stuff
like that but it's really because he wants to pressure pressure the italian government to shut
down the third launch place which is uh genoa in italy and of course the dock workers have said like if
if that happens they'll shut down the port and stuff like that so it's getting really it's it's
developing into a really uh spicy interesting story going forward so we we the psychological
operations have definitely started uh itamar ben gavir our favorite like chill guy totally chilled out
dude said said that like once we're interdicted and detained we're going to long-term terror prisons in
order to uh dissuade um dissuade further activists for attempting this endeavor which is to deliver
humanitarian aid to a beleaguered population that is facing annihilation which is an act protected
under international law so he wants to send like our boat full of like eight honorably discharged
military veterans greta thumberg greta thumberg and a lot of other um journalists into some sort of like
state gulag in order to punish us for like having the audacity to give like baby formula which we
actually have aid on these boats guys two children so yeah and then then he also said in the same
statement that he's gonna turn all these boats into a police force oh wow and i was like bro bro you
should absolutely use this as a police force really good for slow chases my my boat actually doesn't have
bow thrusters so it can't even dock without assistance so they should definitely use this
for their new cop boats so tell me tell me about the veteran boat because i you know i donated i was
pushing i saw a lot of people got behind um you know your boat but i think a lot of people didn't
necessarily know about like the different types of boats you know and and and uh formations that are
happening yeah so i'm on the vet boat there's like the media boat there's the women's boat there's
boats from uh that have delegations from 44 different countries but i really uh scrambled last minute to
make the veteran boat thing happen because we're running in an information war for the existential
survival of the people of gaza and you know in order to fight fascism on the homeland so you know we
were used because of like the militarization of american society we thought you know it'd be a good
idea to kind of leverage the whole veteran status thing because we're a difficult like rhetorical
thing to deal with yes like calling us i did four deployments in a special operations unit like comparing
me to al-qaeda is kind of like absurd i'm just gonna leave it there um you know so it doesn't uh yeah so we
kind of added a layer of security for the fleet because the only the only protection the flotilla
has this humanitarian flotilla has that's not supported really diplomatically by anybody we
don't have like military infrastructure to run large-scale naval operations which is what we're
trying to do we don't have like a tax base that we can allocate funds for you know x amount of resources
so we're basically just cobbling this thing together trying to make it work um but we we think that the
only security that we have is the information war that we're like waging against like genocidal
israeli military propaganda and that's the only safety we have so introducing veterans into it
because of you know the cultural and social capital that we have in our society the society that is the
empire uh we add a little extra layer of security and also we um have the opportunity to explain to
people and to make the movement the palestine movement more intersectional uh because we can
speak with authority that like whatever violence or oppression we allow to happen overseas always
is used on the home front you know whatever our government is willing to do to palestinians
or allow to be done to palestinians well you know they'll do it to you eventually so um
um like i don't know why people don't i know they well because two plus two is seven in this world
that we're in so it's actually it's not even a number i feel like two plus two is starfish like
it's just whatever people want it to be um what do you guys what does the summit flotilla what does the
veterans vote what does greg stoker want from those of us who are at home to uh to do to help to
support to amplify etc okay so first of all we are attempting to run the blockade and establish
a humanitarian corridor into gaza we actually have aid a lot of these boats are small look that's a
small boat um but there are some larger ones uh but we basically just want to land dump the aid go
back to another port and establish a humanitarian corridor uh they will try to stop it which is an
illegal action uh but you know that's not exactly going to stop them and uh basically just go from
there we want to use this uh pr to spread awareness about what's actually going on and me personally i
want to teach a doctrine of intersectionality between different movements and the best way to do that is
by talking about ice um recently the intercept i think like yesterday the intercept broke uh the story
that uh ice is now using uh spyware from paragon technologies they're specifically their graphite
program which basically breaks your phone wide open your contact list your messaging everything you've
ever done on your phone including signal we believe uh is no longer secure and uh that that was tested
guess what guess who was the lab rat for that it was the palestinians in the west bank um so yeah if
if you are calling for the abolition of ice but not speaking out about palestine because it's complicated
or you love the democratic party uh yeah that's dumb it's dumb it's done so there you go so there you
guys have a very clear initiative so the coalition building happens also in coalition of communication
and drawing the lines and and connecting the dots um what would what do you guys do all day
well so we've been and i've been on a boat and there ain't much to do
well we we have a lot to do i've been doing media interviews um a lot of the crew has been running
drills you know we have like man overboard drills we've got like fire drills uh cooking takes a long
time the kitchen's tiny i'm like six foot four it's a nightmare um then then uh what we're concerned
about is drone drills because uh i don't remember if you guys were if you guys recall the conscience
in may they dropped a loitered munition on the ship's engine uh and actually blew it up so we're
running drone drills uh basically like if the drone is spotted in a close orbit around the ship
everybody like gets on deck and uh basically prepares to abandon ship we don't know what they're
gonna do they're a rogue actor right now we've already been buzzed by multiple drones um what does
that mean like they come overhead and just like check yeah like basically just like check you out
and then leave we we haven't seen any like intimidation techniques where they have like
a really close holding pattern and they're just like buzzing around you all night which is what
they do in gaza and it's what they've done on to previous flotillas that have approached the israeli
coastline um so yeah just basically how to handle that as well yeah uh but again it's going to get
pretty boring so i'm probably going to be doing a lot of lives just you know talking to people
shooting this shit did you bring because that's the type of stuff yeah what books are you reading
on the flotilla greg yeah i mean i'm not in the place where i can really like just chill out and enjoy
a novel so i brought i'm going to reread black shirts and reds by michael parenti and then the
think tank racket by glenn decent so that's what i brought and then i mostly have audio books because
i don't know now that i'm old at 35 like reading actual physical books puts me to sleep which is
annoying hilarious that you think as a 44 year old i find it hilarious that you think 35 is old
because it is yeah well okay well both could definitely do something for the stomach i feel
yeah well yeah okay so basically basically everybody got seasick the other night including
including including like very experienced crew because it was just crazy uh it's kind of like
you know you're sitting in the back of the car on a bumpy road and you're just looking at your cell
phone doom scrolling but like 10 times worse that's like seasickness
i'm i'm i'm like living it and i don't want to be um well we will stay in touch you know we can do
this as many times as you'd like as you'd like to um and i also want to know uh basically is there
any expectation that they will show up different that the israelis will show up different with all
these boats um than they have in the in the past like what what what do you guys or do you even want
to speak to that oh i could totally speak to it i believe like part of our whole strategy especially
coming from the veteran boat is to call out what they might do before they do it in order to like
make it politically non-viable in the global forum so yeah they can drop drones on us but like what
we've been watching through open source like uh companies and intelligence firms uh that you know
publish this stuff online they've they've launched a number they've reallocated a bunch of surveillance
craft from israel to uh sigonella air force base which is a u.s naval air station in sicily
um in anticipation to uh run reconnaissance and surveillance on the flotilla and uh also some
of these planes that they've um brought in have like pretty sophisticated and powerful electronic
warfare capabilities so you know they can just fly over our formation and just blow out everyone's
comms vhf radio starlink then you got nothing so that would that would put an end to the flotilla real
quick wait how does there's a lot of things that they can do how do they just blow out the comms
without blowing up their boats well no because it only like their their signals only um target um
electronic systems oh so mostly radio in the 90s you're like amanda they emit they emit a signal that
that wow that's deep so do you remember the james bond movie golden eye it was all about like
electronic warfare and it would like destroy all the electronics and like the helicopters crashed
yeah so that's what they're doing yeah but like not that crazy they'll just like make radio stop working
forever just that all right um yeah cool cool man well we are definitely over here um you know trying
to keep everyone as notified and uh amplifying what you guys are doing because i really do believe the
visibility and the communication around the summit flotilla is part of what protects it um and so i'm
glad to hear that that is confirmed um and i definitely want to make sure that we continue
to do these how many more days do you think he'll be at sea oh it's gonna take a minute like see these
that's a sailboat okay that's sailboat so we're thinking at least another two weeks yeah plenty of content to
be made whoa all right yeah all right so then i'm gonna i'm gonna compile questions from folks for our
next one okay because this one was off the cuff because you know you you're you're like you want
to jump over jump on but now i'm like oh they're gonna be out there for two weeks so i'm coming prepared
next time i'm coming prepared all right let's let's do it all right will you stay safe shout out to all
of you all thank you for your service particularly in this particular regard yeah this one's better
yeah definitely better definitely better stay safe stoker all right see you later bye